# Nikita Khomitsevych

Ukraine, Kyiv | Ready to Relocation | Remote is preferable

E-mail: hamsternik9@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/khomitsevych

Skype: mr.mines\_48

# **Objective**

I'm a 5-year software engineer mostly worked with iOS B2B/B2C applications. Always dealing as a team member developed the bunch of products for any kind of end-users (outsourcing / outstaffing / product). Nowadays I'm looking for an outstanding product which is flawless for users but meantime complex and interesting from engineering perspective. Furthermore, despite of the broad technical expertise I am looking for a leading position which will drive and motivate me to grow together with a company.

#### Skills

- Swift (4 years), Objective-C (less than a year)
- Application architectures: MVC / VIPER / RIB / Redux
- Frameworks
  - [system] Foundation / UIKit / CoreAnimation / AVFoundation / AVKit / CoreLocation / CoreBluetooth / XCTest
  - [third-party] Alamofire / Lottie / Runes, Quick/Nimble, SwiftyMock.
  - o [analytics] Firebase / FB SDK / Amplitude / AppsFlyer / Intercom.
- Automatization: Fastlane / Sourcery / Swiftgen
- Delivery: Jenkins / CircleCI / Bitrise

# **Experience**

### Senior Software Engineer @ Life360 / NCube

January 2020 - present

Life360 iOS Application

Developing the world's leading real-time, location-sharing Life 360 app. Working as the out staff team member in a 4-people iOS engineering crew. Using RIB / Rx / XCTest as major app frameworks to build the solid-based long-term solution. Our goal was the "quality of speed" invariant leads our release cycle to the high-quality product.

#### iOS Software Engineer @ BetterMe USA

November 2018 - December 2019

- Has developed the set of fastest-growing Health & Fitness apps in the world, aimed to improve people's fitness level and general health status. Working with a great team of professionals I personally have developed from scratch or be a part of long-term supporting and upgrading all available iOS applications in AppStore.
- Participating in development I'm implemented a Redux architecture on most of our apps from scratch or migrate existed projects from VIPER to Redux instead. Working on full delivery lifecycle I used Jenkins as CI/CD platform. Fastlane as a primary tool to develop a strict but easy-to-use workflow to eliminate main set of problems related to develop / test / delivery iOS apps. Ruby as main script language to write some small extra tools to simplify own workflow thoroughly.

#### **Developed applications**

- BetterMe: Weight Loss Workouts
- BetterMen: Workout Trainer
- BetterMe: Calm, Sleep, Meditate
- BetterMe: Yoga for Weightloss
- BetterMe: Walking & Weightloss
- BetterMe: Weight Loss Running

## Mobile software engineer @ KaaloT Technologies

June 2017 - September 2018

Nuvo - iOS app for the real-time health monitoring of the pregnant woman and fetus.

Technology Stack: Swift / VIPER / UIKit / CoreGraphics / SwftCharts / Bluetooth Classic /

CoreLocation / Alamofire / RxSwift / Swinject / Nimble / Quick / Cuckoo.

#### Responsibilities

- Writing applications for iPhone/iPad (from iOS 9.0 up to 11.0).
- Feature and application architecture planning.
- Work with IoT devices, connected by Bluetooth Classic.
- R&D department, medical product experience.
- Comply with FDA certification, MFi certification.
- Agile / Scrum workflow.

### iOS Software Engineer @ CyberVision

April 2016 - May 2017

Kaa iOS SDK

Tech Stack: Objective-C / AFNetworking / sqlite3 / Avro Apache / OCMockito.

#### Responsibilities

- Responsibility for immediate bugfix during iOS SDK support.
- Partial SDK migration from manual script installation to the cocoapods workflow.
- SDK integration and continuous support in several active client iOS applications.

#### CleanSpace, iOS SDK

Swift / UIKit / Autolayout / CoreGraphics / CoreBluetooth / CoreLocation / Alamofire / PromiseKit.

#### Responsibilities

- Provided a full cycle of application development (architecture, development, testing).
- Writing third-party frameworks from scratch for next integration on the iOS application.
- Creating Objective-C library that enables communication with BLE peripheral.
- Creating Swift library implemented iBeacon communication workflow.

### Junior iOS/OS X Developer @ dStudio LLC

October 2015 - April 2016

RecApp (iOS Application)

Tech Stack: Objective-C / UIKit / Autolayout / CoreGraphics / CoreAnimation / AVFoundation / AFNetworking / CocoaLumberjack / MVC.

Responsibilities: (1) supporting and updating existed iOS application, (2) creating new features with next integration, (3) experience at implementation of custom UI/UX design, (4) using git as a version control software.

#### Education

09/01/2013 - 06/30/2017 — NTUU "Kyiv Polytechnic Institute", Faculty of biomedical engineering, Computer Science, Bachelor's degree.

09/01/2017 - 12/31/2018 — NTUU "Kyiv Polytechnic Institute", Faculty of biomedical engineering, Computer Science, Master's degree.